Guide to the G. Evelyn Hutchinson Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Personal Files, 1916-1991; Series IV
  - Awards, citations, honors
    - Tyler Ecology Award, 1974 (Box 102, Folder 12)
    - National Academy of Sciences' Award for Environmental Quality in honor of Frederick Gardner Cottrell, 1974 (Box 102, Folder 13)
    - Duke University [honorary degree], 1975 (Box 102, Folder 14)
    - Northwestern University [honorary degree], 1978 (Box 102, Folder 15)
    - Franklin Medal, 1979 (Box 102, Folder 16)
    - Addison Emery Verrill Medal, 1981 (Box 102, Folder 17)
    - Cambridge University [honorary degree], 1981 (Box 102, Folder 18)
    - National Academy of Sciences' Daniel Giraud Elliot Medal, 1984 (Box 102, Folder 19)
    - Kyoto Prize, 1986 (Box 103, Folder 20)
  - Bibliographies, 1964, undated (Box 103, Folder 21)
  - Biographical material, undated (Box 103, Folder 22)
  - Family papers
    - History, undated (Box 103, Folder 23)
    - Hutchinson, Arthur and Evaline Shipley, 1931-1984 (Box 103, Folder 24)
    - Hutchinson, Margaret
      - General, 1924-1983 (Box 103, Folder 25)
      - Letters from Pearl Young, 1939-1948, undated (Box 103, Folder 26-28)
      - Writings, 1951, 1956, undated (Box 103, Folder 29)
    - Johnstone, Sarah E., 1923-1938 (Box 103, Folder 30)
    - Pickford, Grace
      - General, 1925-1926, 1931 (Box 103, Folder 31)
      - Letters from Edith Stephens, [circa 1928-1931] (Box 103, Folder 32)
      - Obituaries and memorial tributes, 1986-1987 (Box 103, Folder 33)
      - Writings and notes, 1948, undated (Box 103, Folder 34)
    - Shipley, A. E., 1916 (Box 104, Folder 35)
    - Shipley family, undated (Box 104, Folder 36)
  - Illustrations [original drawings], undated (Box 113, Folder 3)
  - Memorabilia
    - General, [circa 1961-1990] (Box 104, Folder 37)
      - Oversize (Box 113, Folder 3)
    - Italy [scrapbook of photographs, drawings, and postcards], 1925-1926 (Box 104, Folder 38)
    - National Academy of Sciences centennial celebration, 1963 (Box 104, Folder 39)
    - Smithsonian bicentennial celebration, 1965 (Box 104, Folder 40)
    - Retirement party, 1971 (Box 104, Folder 41)
    - Eightieth birthday celebration, 1983 (Box 104, Folder 42)
  - Obituaries and memorial tributes, 1991 (Box 104, Folder 43)
  - Student notebooks [Cambridge University]
    - 1922-1923, undated (Box 104, Folder 44-45)
    - 1922-1923, undated (Box 105, Folder 46-55)
    - 1922-1923, undated (Box 106, Folder 56-63)
    - 1922-1923, undated (Box 107, Folder 64-72)
- Photographs, 1875-1991; Series V
  This series includes photographs that document Hutchinson's personal life and professional career. The earliest photographs are of family members, but there are numerous pictures of Hutchinson as a young child. There are many other photographs of people and events in Hutchinson's life, including a pictorial record of the childhood and adult life of Yemaiel Oved Aris. The images from Hutchinson's travels and research, particularly those taken as part of the Yale North India Expedition, are especially noteworthy.
  - Hutchinson, G. Evelyn
    - General, [circa 1903-1991], undated (Box 108, Folder 1-5)
    - Princeton University [honorary degree], 1961 (Box 108, Folder 6)
    - Niagara University [honorary degree], 1969 (Box 108, Folder 7)
    - Browning Award ceremony, 1971 (Box 108, Folder 8)
    - Tyler Ecology Award ceremony, 1974 (Box 108, Folder 9)
    - Cottrell Award ceremony, 1974 (Box 108, Folder 10)
    - Northwestern University [honorary degree], 1978 (Box 108, Folder 11)
    - Franklin Medal award ceremony, 1979 (Box 108, Folder 12)
    - Marsh Lecture and Verrill Award ceremony, 1981 (Box 108, Folder 13)
    - Cambridge University [honorary degree ceremony], 1981 (Box 108, Folder 14)
  - Family, friends and acquaintances
    - General, [circa 1875-1980] (Box 108, Folder 15-17)
    - Aris, Yemaiel Oved
      - Infancy and early childhood, [1938 [circa 194-] (Box 108a, Folder 18-19)
      - Teenage and adult, [circa 195-]- 1968] (Box 109, Folder 20-21)
    - Hutchinson, Arthur and Eveline, [188-]-[193-] (Box 109, Folder 22)
    - Hutchinson, Arthur Leslie and family, 1919-1940 (Box 109, Folder 23)
    - Hutchinson, Dorthea, 1979 (Box 109, Folder 24)
  - Travel and research
    - Aden, [1932?] (Box 109, Folder 25)
    - Africa, 1926-1928 (Box 109, Folder 26-27)
    - Bermuda Biological Station, undated (Box 109, Folder 28)
    - England, 1984, undated (Box 109, Folder 29)
    - Goa, 1932 (Box 109, Folder 30-31)
    - Guano, undated (Box 110, Folder 32)
    - Hulch, level 752, undated (Box 110, Folder 33)
    - India
      - General, 1932 (Box 110, Folder 34-37)
      - Agra; Taj Mahal, 1932 (Box 110, Folder 38)
      - Art and architecture
        - General, 1932 (Box 110, Folder 39)
        - Alchi, 1932 (Box 110, Folder 40)
        - Conjeeveran [Kanchipuran], 1932 (Box 110, Folder 41)
        - Mahabalipuram, 1932 (Box 110, Folder 42)
        - Nuhat Bagh, 1932 (Box 110, Folder 43)
      - Benares, 1932 (Box 110, Folder 44)
      - Delhi, 1932 (Box 110, Folder 45)
      - Gia, 1932 (Box 110, Folder 46)
      - Kashmir, 1932 (Box 110, Folder 47-48)
      - Mountain lakes and streams, 1932 (Box 111, Folder 49-50)
      - Mountain terrain, 1932 (Box 111, Folder 51)
      - People, 1932 (Box 111, Folder 52)
      - Religious events, 1932 (Box 111, Folder 53)
    - Insect wing cases, undated (Box 111, Folder 54-55)
    - Italy
      - General, 1925-1926 (Box 111, Folder 56)
        See also: Series IV, box 104, folder 38
      - Lago di Monterosi, undated (Box 111, Folder 57)
    - Lakes, undated (Box 111, Folder 58-60)
      - Oversize (Box 113, Folder 4)
    - Lillie, Dennis [caricatures], undated (Box 111, Folder 61)
    - Madeira and the Canaries, undated (Box 111, Folder 62)
    - Nemerteans, undated (Box 111, Folder 63)
    - South Africa, undated (Box 111, Folder 64)
    - Tibet, 1932 (Box 111, Folder 65)
    - Yale North India Expedition, 1932 (Box 112, Folder 66)
  - Unidentified, undated (Box 112, Folder 67-69)
- Additional material, 1937-1941; Accession 2007-M-030
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Transferred from Kline Science Library, Yale University, 2006.
  This accession comprises articles written by G. Evelyn Hutchinson.
  - "The Biological Elements", 1939 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Lectures Notes on Limnology", 1941 (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
  - "Limnological Studies in Indian Tibet", 1937 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Additional material, 1948-1990; Accession 2009-M-082
  Gift of Nancy Slack, 2009.
  Appraisal
  Photocopies and notecards (1 linear foot) containing readily available bibliographic information on scientific literature were removed from the collection during processing.
  This accession comprises a small amount of correspondence to and from Hutchinson, notes and drafts relating to his professional writings, and an album of photographic negatives documenting part of Hutchinson's trip on the Silk Road in the border region between India and Tibet.
  - Correspondence, 1948-1990 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Notes and drafts, Circa 1970-1990 (Box 1, Folder 2-4)
  - "Ladak: paintings, lakes," Kodak negative album, Circa 1950s (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Unstable cellulose nitrate negatives contained in this album were removed, digitized, and then destroyed. The album itself was retained because of the informative notes it contains relating to some of the images.